<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Neil Chen</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Neil Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pressure and failure</title>
      <link>/post/2021/02/02/pressure-and-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021/02/02/pressure-and-failure/</guid>
      <description>This is a running list of some of my favorite accounts of personal rejection or failure (narrowly: in school and in tech).
 Ian Goodfellow Ian Goodfellow&amp;rsquo;s name is now roughly synonymous with &amp;ldquo;deep learning&amp;rdquo;, but he describes plenty of personal risks, subsequent failures, and post-facto views on them:
 I once applied for a summer internship with a Stanford professor. My transcript was included in my application. He replied “Why do you have an A in my class?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vim-repl workflow</title>
      <link>/post/2021/01/16/vim-repl-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021/01/16/vim-repl-workflow/</guid>
      <description>One of the tools I wish I&amp;rsquo;d known about sooner is vim-repl. It&amp;rsquo;s a vim plugin that opens an interactive REPL, configurable based on source file type (.py, .hs, .scala, &amp;hellip;)
 A REPL, or read-eval-print-loop, lets you input, evaluate, and output expressions without having to (for example) compile an entire program.
 I used to run this workflow using SLIME and tmux. Before that, if I wanted a development environment with a tight feedback loop between writing &amp;amp; evaluating code, I defaulted to a Jupyter notebook &amp;ndash; which, for this purpose, is probably both the wrong tool to use and often (for me) unsustainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hand tools and spare time</title>
      <link>/note/2021/01/11/hand-tools-and-spare-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/note/2021/01/11/hand-tools-and-spare-time/</guid>
      <description>If you, with no prior training, picked up a 1/2&amp;quot; chisel, a handsaw, a rubber mallet, and a Home Depot bench plane, you&amp;rsquo;d arrive at a reasonable approximation of my 2020.
Workbench This is a hastily-made workbench/work-from-home standing desk. The legs are 3.5&amp;quot; douglas fir and joined via mortise-and-tenon. The top surface is 1.5&amp;quot; thick fir. Half-finished:

To handle racking, there are three chunky sections of pine joined by cross laps to the legs of the bench.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genki Sudo</title>
      <link>/note/2021/01/07/genki-sudo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/note/2021/01/07/genki-sudo/</guid>
      <description>Genki Sudo is a member of the upper house of Japan&amp;rsquo;s bicameral legislature. Western folks like myself might have unwittingly encountered him via these 2000s music videos of his music group World Order.
Before all this, Sudo was a professional mixed martial artist. He fought in several promotions, but in every arena he introduced himself idiosyncratically. Sudo choreographed WWE-like entrances that included:
 himself doing the robot with a KFC bucket hat, himself as a baseball player, himself in Samurai garb,  and ended every fight carrying the flag of his motto, &amp;ldquo;We Are All One&amp;rdquo;:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A paper on soft-muscle actuation</title>
      <link>/post/2020/06/15/a-paper-on-soft-muscle-actuation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/06/15/a-paper-on-soft-muscle-actuation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s published! For several months in college I worked with Professor Hod Lipson&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.creativemachineslab.com/&#34;&gt;Creative Machines Lab&lt;/a&gt; on building a &amp;ldquo;soft actuator&amp;rdquo;. The goal was to build an electrically-powered &amp;ldquo;muscle&amp;rdquo; geometry out of silicone; our approach was to drive contraction and expansion thermally.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing 1.5 years of diary entries</title>
      <link>/post/2019/06/24/analyzing-1.5-years-of-diary-entries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/06/24/analyzing-1.5-years-of-diary-entries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote 39,000+ words across 223 entries in my diary in the last 1.5 years. Could I learn more about my mood/emotions by analyzing my diary? I wrote some Python to find out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a T-shirt shooting robot</title>
      <link>/post/2017/01/01/building-a-t-shirt-shooting-robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017/01/01/building-a-t-shirt-shooting-robot/</guid>
      <description>I have an amateur and casual interest in robotics, from mechanical design to grasping and manipulation. In my first year of college, I played with the idea of building a 100lb. t-shirt shooting robot to drive around &amp;amp; eject shirts into crowds. We were very fortunate to get a bit of money from a student group on campus, access to the Columbia University MakerSpace, and a few dumpsters with nice DC motors and aluminum extrusion sitting around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m from Queens, NY. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in MMA, robotics, and software systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jessie&#39;s baked creations!</title>
      <link>/bakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bakes/</guid>
      <description>More-whole-wheat bread 01/30/21 Walnut &amp;amp; cinnamon raisin bread 01/30/21  Lemon, blueberry, and greek yogurt whole wheat almond cake 01/24/21  Banana bread 01/23/21  Lemon meringue cupcakes 01/16/21  Milk bread 01/10/21  01/06/21  01/03/21  Sponge cake 12/31/20  12/29/20 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
